

Alex Severianov

iOS/macOS Developer

CONTACT



@Alexizh



alex.severyanov@gmail.com



https://github.com/AlexIzh



/in/alex-severyanov-7a2403aa/

PROFILE

First 6 years of my carreer worked at consulting company, as result developed a lot of different applications there as and solo developer so and a team-player. I was a team leader for huge smart-home universal iOS/iPad app and for big social network app.

Besides apple platforms, I have experience with Kotlin (developed a multiplatform library for iOS and Android), Ruby (CI scripts), flutter (pet project) and more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer, team lead nebenan.de | Sep. 2017

iOS app development of social networking app, setup CI, mentoring junior developers.

MacOS Developer

OnQ Systems GmbH | Apr, 2017 - Sep, 2017

macOS development of application for making payments in Switzerland, payment info recognition by camera, windows tools for users migration.

iOS Developer MQD BV | Dec, 2011 - Mar, 2017

Outsourcing company. I developed a lot of applications there, was a leader for a couple of projects and also I wrote technical documentation(for projects, style guides, other conventions) for an iOS team.

EDUCATION

Specialist of diploma (IT Engineer) Udmurt State University | 2010 - 2015

LANGUAGES

Russian: native

English: upper intermediate

LOCATIONS

Born in Russia, now living in Georgia and often visiting Turkey. Going to relocate to Slovakia next year.